Rizwan UD

Contact No: +92(302)2804717 Email Address: <u>rizwanud1993@gmail.com</u> LinkedIn Profile: <u>linkedin.com/in/rizwan-ud-40917a73</u>

Application Manager & Business Analyst

Personal Statement

Competent, results-oriented professional with proven 6-years professional experience in many technologies seeking a challenging and growth-oriented position in technical position.

Proven records of work in international teams in local industries, different countries. Managing well various business application, successfully supporting in Design and Development.

I'm the person, who works collaboratively to get the job done even under pressure and always well prepared to mitigate risk.

Experience

Application Support Analyst/Business Analyst/PMO, Citi Bank N.A. Pakistan

Aug 2019 – Present

Accomplishes information technology staff results by communicating job expectations; planning, monitoring, and appraising job results; coaching, counseling, and disciplining employees; initiating, coordinating, and enforcing systems, policies, and procedures.

Maintains organization's effectiveness and efficiency by defining, delivering, and supporting strategic plans for implementing information technologies.

Directs technological research by studying organization goals, strategies, practices, and user projects. Completes projects by coordinating resources and timetables with user departments and data center. Verifies application results by conducting system audits of technologies implemented.

Preserves assets by implementing disaster recovery and back-up procedures and information security and control structures. Also working on GDPR process which have complied by central bank and Global Initiatives. Around the world, data protection and privacy legislation is increasingly important and a crucial part of overall IT Governance, and increasingly onerous. It is in this field, in particular, that new laws are emerging on a regular basis. Many of these overlaps, or contradict existing laws, and for few of them is there any detailed regulatory implementation guidance or meaningful case law. Also, worked on JSON with our regulatory project and delivered as per the deadline. We integrate Restful Api with our system via JSON request response will be deliver.

Business Technology Partner, Bank Alfalah Ltd, Pakistan.

June 2018 – 2019

Expertise in Remittance & Forex payment Services, Operations, Business Development Activities, CRM & Back Office Operations across Banking and Financial Industry.

Dynamic professional offering experience of 4 years in the industry with main forte lying in the area of Back Office Operations in Banking & Financial process with comprehensive skills in strategic and time management planning.

Integration of MOBILE WALLET which helps customer to credit their transaction in wallet then can easily withdrawal their remittance via Mobile numbers. This project based on regulators.

REMITTANCE, CASH MANAGEMENT & FOREX OPERATIONS Specialist.

Remittance Portal Assistance PRI & Correspondents as a PMO

CASH Management Application Support & Project Coordinator

Enterprise Project Management EPM

Restful Api test via SOAP UI

Consume RestAPI for cash over the counter transactions.

Using JavaScript/HTML for validation and controls.

Almost 55 agents integrated all over the work in the banking system

Software Developer (Prime HR), Bank Alfalah Ltd, Pakistan.

November 2016 – June 2018

Expertise in Remittance & Forex payment Services, Operations, Business Development Activities, CRM & Back Office Operations across Banking and Financial Industry.

Dynamic professional offering experience of 4 years in the industry with main forte lying in the area of Back Office Operations in Banking & Financial process with comprehensive skills in strategic and time management planning. REMITTANCE, CASH MANAGEMENT & FOREX OPERATIONS Specialist.

Jr. Software Engineer (K-tabs) Bank Alfalah Ltd, Pakistan

December 2015 – November 2016

Create Linked Server to TERA DATA and SQL SERVER. Working on (Lease Management System) which is role on more than 500+ branches in all over PAKISTAN. Client end support and Queries, ETL's, Trigger's, SP's analysis and execution. Database actions like creation of link server, restoring dB, Backup db. Configuration of virtual servers for deployment and Development of Web Banking. Review, to the extent possible, changes in system to analyze the impact of changes in system performance. Testing new programs and fault reporting. To prioritize and meet deadlines. Coordinates and actively participates in all stages of Software development including analysis, design, development, testing and implementation

Internship Business Intelligence Unit (.Net Developer), Silk Bank., Pakistan

October 01 - November 30, 2015

Collect data from different systems (T24, Oracle, SQL Server, Excel, and CSV) i.e., sources for different products and amalgamate them into one place. The data belonged to different products offered by the bank including Liabilities, Loans, and Credit Cards.

Automate the Sales and Non - Sales staff commissions of Silk Bank for both Islamic and Conventional.

Former Internship System Engineer, Pakistan International Airlines (PIA), Pakistan

January 01 – April 01, 2013

Worked here as a system administrator. My Responsibility to look after or maintain personal computer diagnose and analyses the problem

Education

EMBA from Karachi University Business School (In progress)

Bachelors in Computer Science Dadabhoy University, Tariq Road, Karachi, Pakistan, September (2018).

Skills

Computer skills

.Net, SQL, C#, Android, Windows Server 2008, 2012, Teradata, Oracle 11g, VMWare. EPM, Agile, Service now Suit, SAP Business intelligence, Archer, JSON, HTML, JavaScript, API, Integration, Restful, SoapUI.

Communication Skills

Excellent written and verbal communication skills.

Confident, articulate, and professional speaking abilities (and experience)

Empathic listener and persuasive speaker.

Writing creative or factual.

Speaking in public, to groups, or via electronic media.

Excellent presentation and negotiation skills.

Active listening and paying close attention to the person who is speaking to you.

Adapting your communication style to your audience.

Friendliness.

Confidence.

Giving and receiving feedback.

	Volume and clarity.
	Volume and clarity. Empathy. Respect.
<u>Hobb</u>	<u>iies</u>
	Swimming, Reading, Listening, Football Player, Gaming